NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files. 6174/018
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Committee of 100, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  05/11-12/09. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, higher education, health and safety issues, labor and retirement)
- Committee of 100, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  05/11-12/09 in Desmond Hotel. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, higher education, health and safety issues, labor and retirement, social justice)
- Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute 2008 Sponsorship Options (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Informational brochure
- Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  9/7-10/08 in DC. AFT memo re institute's Public Policy Conference; materials re annual gala
- Contract for Excellence Update Meeting, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  4/10/08 at 2:30pm in Hilton, NYC. Discussion paper for Regents, "Proposed Revisions to the Regulations of the Commissioner Relating to Contracts for Excellence," February 5; memo from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to locals re Contract for Excellence update and meeting, March 11
- Anne Schiano Meeting: They will meet after the Regents, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  01/13/09.Memos re meeting date; paper by Justin Minkel, 2997 Arkansas Teacher of the Year, "Reflections on Education Policy Related to English Learners"; draft chart, "Performance Indicators with Benchmarks Integrating ESL Performance Indicators into the ELA/ESL Revised Standards"
- ELA/ESL Standards Review Panel, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  6/26-27/2008. Agenda for June 26-27 meeting of the ELA/ESL Standards Review Panel
- ELA/ESL Standards, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  4/24/08. Draft document, "Educating English Language Learners: What the Research Does -- and Does Not -- Tell Us"; agenda for Regents Learning Standards Review Initiative Public Forum on the Review of the ELA/ESL Standards
- ELA/ESL Panel (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Panel recommendations and researchers
- ELA/ESL Learning Standards DRAFT Versions, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Presentation outline of Regents Standards Review Initiative at Board of Regents meeting, December 15, 2008; Partnership for the 21st Century Skills Review of NYS Standard English Language Arts K-12, January 22, 2009; draft reading performance indicators for pre-kindergarten, grade 5, and grade 9
- ESL Reseachers, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Individual biographies of ESL researchers
- Spanish/Hispanic/Latino Quotations, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  6/5/08. Quotations on leadership and the Latino experience
- Hispanic Participation in Technology Careers Summit, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  5/5-6/08. Report prepared for summit, "A Matter of Trust: Ten Key Insights from Recent Public Opinion Research on Attitudes about Education Among Hispanic Parents, Students, and Young Adults"
- Hispanic Federation: Reform Agenda, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Report, "Confronting the Latino Academic Achievement Gap: A Reform Agenda"
- Janella Hinds Conference Call, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  11/05/09 at 2PM. Report of the NYSUT High School Initiatives Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates
- Credit Recovery, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  11/06/08 at 1PM in SED, NYC. NYSUT Talking Points on Credit Recovery, the practice of allowing students to make up for lack of classroom attendance, sometimes through online courses, in order to improve school district graduation rates; article from New York Times, April 11, 2008; reports/marketing materials by online learning companies
- NYSUT High School Initiative Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Agenda for task force meeting, October 15; draft report; articles; related materials; handwritten notes
- High School Initiative Task Force, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  09/22/08 at 10AM in NYSUT HQ. Memos; agenda for NEA Leadership Forum
- High School Initiatives Task Force, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  05/14/08 at 10AM in NYSUT HQ. Agenda; handwritten outline of problem; presentation, "NYS High School Graduation and Dropout Rates: Looking at Low Performing Students"; recommendations; related materials
- High School Initiatives Task Force - Maria, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  05/14/08. Agenda; timeline; list of members; related materials
- NYSUT HS Initiatives Task Force, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  2/8/08. Summary by Fact Finders, "2008 NYSUT HS Initiatives Student and Parent Study"
- Task Force on High School Initiatives, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  Charge to the task force; background re establishment of task force; list of members; reports of the first vice president (Maria Neira), updating on high school initiative, prepared for the NYSUT Board of Directors
- FAIR: Legislative Analysis, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  The DREAM Act (Development, Relief, and Education for Alien Minors Act of 2007) legislative analysis by Federation for American Immigration Reform
- NYSUT Local Action Project Carmel Teacher's Association, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  Tarrytown regional office, local presidents' conference; newsletter; list of LAP events; presentation summary re LAP; memorabilia
- NYSUT Local Action Project, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  7/22/10. Presentation materials, "Defining Excellence in Our Professions," NYSUT Local Action Project, July 22, 2010
- LAP: The Gideon Putnam, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  07/21-24/09. At-a-glance agenda for Local Action Project Conference; related materials
- LAP Committee, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  09/30/08 at 2PM in Conf. Rm. C. List of local funding requests, September 12; LAP budget forms from locals
- LAP Conference, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  7/21-25/08 in Fort Henry, Lake George. NYSUT vice president Maria Neira welcome and opening remarks
- LAP Applications, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  02/29/08 at 11:30AM in Maria's Office. LAP applications from locals
- LAP Summer Planning Conference, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  Summary of participant feedback; evaluation report; thank-you letter to Niera from Association of Career and Technical Education Administrators for use of facility
- Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference Planning Mtg., 2009 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  09/10/09 at 1:30PM in Exec. Rm. 1. Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference Planning Committee minutes, April 24; conference tentative schedule (pre-Representative Assembly); planning committee agenda; summary and results of 2009 Local Presidents Conference Survey
- National Board for Professional Teaching Standards, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  11/06-07/09 in Washington, DC. Registration form for Maria Neira; talking points for Finance Committee telephone call meeting; agenda for NBPTS Board of Directors meeting; highlights of development activities; financial update; report of nominating committee; minutes of meeting of Executive Committee via conference call, October 20
- NBPTS, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  07/15-18/09 in Atlanta, GA. Attendance list for Board of Directors meeting; CDs; publicity materials
- NBPTS: Conflict of Interest Policy, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  Director disclosure statement for Maria Neira; Code of Ethics; Conflict of Interest Policy; related memos
- NBPTS Code of Ethics, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  Code of Ethics; related memo; statement by Maria Neira, "Vote. Get Involved. Make a Difference."
- NBPTS, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  02/28/06. Investment guidelines, June 2003; issues of Education Week; list of committees; fact sheet, "About National Board Certification"; newspaper clippings; Executive Committee meeting agenda, February 28, 2007; minutes of October 13, 2006, meeting; talking points re Harris and Sass research re effects of NBPTS-certified teachers on student achievement
- NBPTS Board of Directors Meeting, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  03/27-28/09. Tabbed materials
- NBPTS Board of Directors Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  04/04-05/08. Tabbed materials
- NBPTS Executive Committee Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  10/20/09 at 4:30PM. Minutes of Executive Committee meeting of May 20, 2009; agenda for October 20 conference call; outline, "Draft Mid-Year Cuts Campaign"
- NBPTS Conf. Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  05/20/09 at 4PM in Maria's office. Minutes of Executive Committee meeting of March 27, 2009; nomination form for James A. Kelly Award for First Lady Michelle Obama; nomination for Kelly Award for Education Secretary Arne Duncan; nomination for Arthur Wise; list of nominees; description of James A. Kelly Award
- NBPTS: President/CEO Performance Assessment, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Performance Planning and Assessment Program materials; memo; schedule
- Performance Goals for President/CEO of NBPTS, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Timeline; memos
- NBPTS Conf. Call, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  9/22/08 at 5PM in Maria's office. Agenda for Executive Committee conference call, August 14; minutes of April 3 meeting; second quarter financial review; performance progress report
- NBPTS Exec. Comm. Conf. Call, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  8/14/08 at 4PM. Agenda for August 14 conference call; president/CEO performance goals; progress report
- NBPTS Executive Committee, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  04/04-05/08 at 10AM TBD. Tabbed materials re president/CEO Performance Planning and Assessment Program
- NBPTS Executive Committee Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  4/3/08 TBD. Tentative agenda; memos; handwritten notes
- NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  10/21/09 at 6:00pm. Agenda; talking points; memos; minutes of September 23 meeting; confidential detailed memo re approval of 2010 general and administrative budget, October 16
- NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  9/23/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of August 24 meeting; financial review
- NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  8/24/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of July 2 meeting; financial review
- NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  05/21/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of March 27 meeting; financial review
- NBPTS: Financial Committee, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  03/27-28/09 in Arlington, VA. Agenda for Finance Committee meeting of March 27; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of March 27; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of November 7, 2008; minutes of Finance Committee meeting of March 3, 2009; memo re office space lease; Report of Finance Committee: 2008 Financial Results and 2009 Comprehensive Budget; memo re leadership competencies assessment for president/CEO
- NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  03/03/09 at 5:30PM. Talking points for meeting; agenda; minutes of February 11 meeting; confidential detailed memo re 2008 estimated results of financial operations
- NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  02/11/09 at 5:30PM. Agenda; talking points; confidential financial overview
- John Zimmerman Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  12/12/08 at 9AM in Dick's office. Letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, congratulating her on her election as chair of NBPTS Finance Committee, November 12, 2008; AFT financial statements
- NBPTS, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  12/04/08 at 12:30PM in Maria's office. Financial report, December 31, 2007; Federal Awards Supplemental Information, December 31, 2007; September 2008 financial review; related memos
- NBPTS Conference and Exhibition, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  07/15-18/09 in Atlanta, Georgia. Conference program
- National Board Certification Program, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Greater Capital Region Teacher Center folder with informational brochures and fact sheets
- NYS & NBPTS, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  July 7, 2008, at Exec. 2. Bullet points
- NBPTS, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  05/16/08 at 3PM in SED. Draft meeting agenda, "Taking Inventory and Moving Forward: National Board Certification in NYS"; related memo
- AFT NBPTS Conference Call, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  02/12/08 at 5PM. Notes from planning meeting 3, "In Pursuit of Excellence: Celebrating the Accomplished Teacher," January 11, 2007; memo and outline of discussion questions for conference call
- NBPTS/Albert Shanker Grant, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Chart of contracts with National Board Certification incentives
- NBPTS Ballot: James A. Kelly Award, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Ballot from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira in her role as member of the Board of Directors of National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; letter to Board of Directors recommending that the James A. Kelly Award for Advancing Accomplished Teaching go to Gov. Roy E. Barnes and Dr. Linda Darling-Hammond
- NBPTS Incumbent Director's Consent-to-Questionnaire Form, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Blank and filled-in forms
- NBPTS Incumbent Director's Consent-to-Serve Questionnaire, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Filled-in form by Maria Neira; instruction to Neira re how to fill out form, including draft responses; blank forms; Report of 2007 Nominating Committee
- NBPTS President/CEO Leadership Competencies Assessment Executive Committee Summary, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Performance plan and related confidential materials
- NBPTS Executive Committee Meeting Materials, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  02/28/07 in Arlington, VA. Agenda; minutes of December 8, 2006, meeting of working group; 2006 Financial Results of Operations; 2003-2006 Selected Progress Indicators; brochure, "Making the Commitment to Accomplished Teaching: Q and A for 2007 National Board Certification"; fact sheet, "About National Board Certification"
- NCLB (No Child Left Behind) Task Force Webcast, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  January 14, 2009 at 2:00-4:30. Agenda; AFT position papers, "Investing in a Well-Qualified Teacher in Every Classroom," "Community Schools," "Focus on High-Achieving Low-Income Students," other issues
- Conf. Call NCLB Task Force Web Meeting, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  1/8/09. Facilitative memos
- Alternative Proposal to NCLB, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  5/22/08 with Lunch at Hilton, Chevy Chase Run (Terrace Level). NCLB Task Force meeting agenda, April 17-18, 2008; statement by Randi Weingarten, president, United Federation of Teachers, to the Association for a Better New York, "Accountability in New York City's Public Schools," March 13, 2008; highlights of the proposed accountability reports; list of NCLB Task Force members; related documents
- NCLB Task Force, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  5/22/08 at 12:15-1:45PM. Memo from executive vice president Antonia Cortese, inviting task force members to attend meeting with AFT vice president Randi Weingarten to develop alternatives to No Child Left Behind accountability proposals
- AFT NCLB Task Force, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  04/17-18/08 in Washington, DC. Overview of the Academic Performance Index; questions for discussion of the Elementary Index; related documents
- NCLB (No Child Left Behind), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  Report by the Commission on No Child Left Behind, "Beyond NCLB: Fulfilling the Promise to Our Nation's Children," 2007; report by the National Middle School Association, "Success in the Middle: A Policymaker's Guide to Achieving Quality Middle Level Education," 2006; other reports and article reprints
- NCLB, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Draft report by the Commission on No Child Left Behind, "Beyond NCLB: Fulfilling the Promise to Our Nation's Children"; Rand Corporation report, "The Role of Districts in Fostering Instructional Improvement: Lessons from Three Urban Districts Partnered with the Institute for Learning," 2005: AFT report, "NCLB: Let's Get It Right," n.d.
- NCLB PowerPoint, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  10/19-20/07. Presentation at NYSUT Board of Directors meeting; document, "Landmark Agreement for Pension Benefits and School-Wide Bonuses Brings Professional Gains to NYC Public School Educators"
- NCLB Task Force Meeting, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  9/14/07 at 2PM in Video Conf. Room. Call for meeting of the No Child Left Behind Task Force
- NCLB Meeting, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  09/06/06 at 10:30AM in Maria's Office. Presentation by Maria Neira to the NYS Association of Black and Puerto Rican Legislators re Campaign for Fiscal Equity, "Can CFE Close the Achievement Gap?" February 18, 2006; memos
- Proposal of NCLB Video, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  Letter from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to Door Knob Films LLC, expressing support for documentary project, "No Teacher Left Behind," referencing $10,000 grant from NYSUT to assist in production, June 24, 2008; copy of check; proposal for video documentary and request for support, with budget, April 5, 2008
- NCLB Growth Model Proposal in Rochester, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Letter from Kenmore Teachers Association to State Education Department
- Miller/Mckeon ESEA Title 1 Draft Bill, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  Memo from Maria Neira to NYSUT officers re NYSUT position on Miller/McKeon draft of reauthorization of Title I of the No Child Left Behind Act
- Gillibrand: NCLB, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  NYSUT document, "NCLB: Time for a Change: Recommendations to the United States Congress," March 12, 2007
- NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  12/18/09 at 11:30AM in Sheraton NY Hotel. Minutes of meeting of June 16, 2009; letter to Maria Neira re December 18 meeting
- NYS AFL-CIO Workforce Development Inst. Conf. Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  06/23/09 at 2:30PM. Facilitative memo
- NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting (Box 2, Folder 47)
  06/16/09 at 12:30PM in Crowne Plaza. Agenda; secretary-treasurer's report; NYS AFL-CIO Budget Analysis for the period July 1, 2008, through March 31, 2009; minutes of December 19, 2008, Executive Council meeting; 2009-2010 Proposed Budget; press advisory, "Join New Yorkers In Support of Their Union Brother's (sic) and Sisters And the Workers of Puerto Rico!" with attached materials, June 15, 2009; brochure re labor law at Fordham Law School; related materials; memo re Senate introduction of 9/11 Health Compensation Fund, June 16, 2009; flyer for national health care reform rally and lobby day, June 28; NYS AFL-CIO Document Retention Policy; Conflict of Interest Policy; Whistleblower Protection Policy; Community Outreach Department Report; Executive Summary, Young Unionists' Conference, May 7-9, 2009
- NYS AFL-CIO/NYC Central Labor Council Executive Board, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  10/22/08 at 12:30PM in Sheraton NY Hotel. Publication by the Fiscal Policy Institute, "The State of Working New York 2007: Encouraging Recent Gains but Troubling Long-Term Trends"; presentation, "With the end of Wall Street as we knew It, what lies ahead? New York's economic and fiscal challenges"; report, "New York's Rising Unemployment: The Other Crisis in Albany"; NYS AFL-CIO document, "Labor 2008: Targeted Races," tracking canvassing activity; flyer invitation to NYS AFL-CIO breakfast in honor of Attorney General Andrew Cuomo
- NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  09/04/08 at 11:30AM in Grand Hyatt, NYC. Draft AFT concept paper, Innovation Fund, September 2, 2008; agenda; conference call meeting minutes, August 26, 2008
- NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  06/17/08 at 11:30AM in Albany, New York. Agenda; meeting minutes of December 7, 2007; NYS AFL-CIO Budget Analysis; 2008-2009 Proposed Budget; Secretary-Treasurer's Report; NYS AFL-CIO Investment Policy; Resolution 2, submitted by AFL-CIO Executive Council, "A Diverse Movement Calls for Diverse Leadership," 2005; charts of targeted NY Congressional Districts; flyers for receptions for political candidates
- NYS AFL-CIO Exec. Council, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  06/17/08 at 11:30AM in Albany Crowne Plaza. Minutes of meeting; facilitative correspondence
- Workforce Development Institute Board Meeting, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  6/11/08 at 10:00AM in the Troy Office. Agenda for Board of Directors meeting; draft employee manual; program reports; Executive Director's Report; financial statements; publications of photographs and stories by workers and families of UAW Local 465 and others, "Unseen America New York State"
- NYS AFL-CIO Rally, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  9/8/07 at 10AM in NYC. Invitation to Maria Neira to Labor Day rally in support of proposed federal legislation for medical monitoring and treatment for 9/11 first responders and other workers whose long-term health was affected by the attack
- NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  07/10/07 in Sheraton, New York. Agenda; report on the BALCONY (Business and Labor Coalition of New York) Universal Health Care Forum, "Affordable Health Care for New York Prescriptions for a Health State"; projected budget
- Peer Review & PSPB, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  05/04/09 at 2PM in Maria's Office. Agenda; evaluation sheets; thank-you letters to seminar panelists
- Peer Review Conf. for Local Leaders, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  12/5/08 at 9AM in Auditorium. Agenda; bio of Antonia Cortese; suggested questions for panel presentation; presentation bullet points; resolution adopted by AFT, Peer Assistance and Review for New Teachers: Taking Charge of Our Profession; issue of AFT American Educator, fall 2008
- NYSUT Peer Review Seminar, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  12/05/08. Agenda; seminar materials; handwritten notes
- Web Meeting - Draft Resolution on Peer Asst. and Review, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  01/17/08. Draft and revised resolutions re peer assistance and review; related memo; instructions for web meeting
- Peer Assistance and Review, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  Comments on draft resolution from Maria Neira
- Senate Democratic Hispanic Task Force Forum, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  6/24/08 at 3PM in Senate Russell Office. Talking points for legislative visits; invitation to Maria Neira from Senators Ken Salazar and Richard Menendez, co-chairs of Senate Democratic Hispanic Task Force, to attend forum with Latino labor union leaders re concerns of working families; handwritten notes; materials on the Employee Free Choice Act; memos
- Somos El Futuro Debrief, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  5/30/08 at 10AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Memo re meeting
- 2009 Somos Conference (Box 2, Folder 62)
  April 2-5, 2009. Memo re logistics of maintaining a NYSUT presence at the Somos conference
- NBPTS Executive Committee Conference Call, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  12/15/09. Agenda; minutes of November 6, 2009, meeting; National Board of Professional Teaching Standards Accomplished Principal Standards
- Somos El Futuro, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  April 25-27, 2008 at the Egg, Albany, NY. Talking points for Maria Neira; NYSUT bullet points, "Fulfilling America's Promise: Improving Educational Opportunities for Hispanic Children," April 25; booklet for luncheon awards program; agenda
- Somos El Futuro, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Caucus Weekend 2008 & Somos El Futuro Conferences memorandum
- Somos El Futuro Puerto Rico, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Program for 2nd Annual Latino Upstate Summit, October 17, 2008; memo to Maria Neira re Somos Conference held in Puerto Rico, with agenda and registration form
- 21st Annual Somos El Futuro Conference, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  On 04/25-27/08 in Albany, New York. Program
- Somos El Futuro 20th Annual Legislative Conference, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)